Register of the Stanley Kuhl Hornbeck papers, 1900-1966
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject and Correspondence File, 1842-1966 (Boxes 1-452)
  - Cadogan, Sir Alexander M. G. (Box 43)
  - Caffery, Jefferson
  - Cairo Conference
  - Calder, Bland
  - Calendar reform, Achelis, 1942-1944
  - Calhoun, Mrs. William James
  - California
  - California - Oregon
  - California Texas Oil Company
  - Callahan, Robert E.
  - Cambodia
  - Campbell, Mrs. Guy
  - Canada IX - 14-58, C. B. C.
  - Canada
  - Canadian Embassy
  - Canadian Legation
  - Canal, Panama
  - Canham, Edwin D.
  - "Can't Happen Here"
  - Capital Airlines, 1956
  - Capitalism and anti-capitalism
  - Capper, Arthur
  - Capper Resolution, S.J. Res. 140
  - Captive Nations
  - Carabao, 1935
  - C.A.R.E.
  - Carlson, Evans F. (Box 44)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace
  - Carnegie Institution
  - Carney, Admiral
  - Carothers, Neil
  - Carothers, recent memos, etc., 1964, 1966
  - Carothers, Neil, "The Chaotic Currency Condition of Europe,", 1924
  - Carpets (Hinckles)
  - Carr, Harry
  - Carr, Wilbur J.
  - Carruth, Tom
  - Carson, Clarence B.
  - Cartels
  - Carter, Boake
  - Carter, Carroll M.
  - Carter, E. C. (Box 45)
  - Carter, E. C. (Box 46)
  - Carter John F.
  - Carter, John Ridgely
  - Cartoons
  - Cartoons, political, "He Bit Me", 1931
  - Cartoons, political, 1941
  - Caruso, Miss Rose A.
  - Casanova, Telesford, Mrs.
  - Casey, Richard G.
  - Cassels, John M.
  - Castle, William Richards, in memoriam, 1963 October
  - Castle, William R.
  - "Castlereagh,", 1906
  - Catholic Church
  - Catholic League
  - Cause and Cure of War (Miss Josephine Schain), 1933-1940 (Box 47)
  - Censorship
  - Cento
  - Central Intelligence Agency
  - Century Association
  - Century Association, 1964-1966
  - Century Company Contract
  - Ceremonial Communications
  - Ceylon
  - Chadbourne, William
  - "Chair"
  - Chamber of Commerce of United States
  - Chamberlain, Sir Austen
  - Chamberlain, Culver B.
  - Chance
  - Chandler, Albert B. (Kentucky)
  - Chandler, George
  - Chandler, George and Bruce and Frances
  - Chang, Alfred Z.
  - Chang, Chung-Fu
  - Chang, Kia-ngau
  - Chang, Dr. L. N.
  - Chang, P. C.
  - Chang, Richard T.
  - Chang Tao-Shing, Dr.
  - Change (Box 48)
  - Chapin, Selden
  - Chapin, Vinton
  - Chaplains' Association of the Army of the United States
  - Chapman, Dr. Carleton B. (The Oxonian)
  - Chapultepec-Inter-American Conference, Mexico City, Act of Chapultepec, 1945 March 3
  - Charlottesville (Kinker and W. Washington), 1954
  - Charlottesville, Legal Forum, 1954
  - Charter, Atlantic
  - Charter, Pacific
  - Chase, A. Sabin
  - Chase, Mr. Frederic L., III, 1966
  - Chase National Bank
  - Chen, Chi-Mai (see also Tong and Chinese Embassy)
  - Chen, King
  - Chen, Nancy, 1965
  - Cheng, Chi-Yuan, Communist China's Economy, 1963
  - Cheng, Judge F. T.
  - Chang, Tsung Hai
  - Chennault, Anne C.
  - Chennalut, Claire L.
  - Cherrington, Ben M.
  - Cherry Blossom Festival, 1934 April
  - Chevrolet, 1954-1963
  - Chevy Chase School (Box 49)
  - Chiang, Hsueh-Ling
  - Chiang, Kai Shek
  - Chiang, Kai Shek, 1944
  - Chiang, Kai Shek and Madame Chiang Kai Shek
  - Chiang, Kai Shek, Christmas message, 1944
  - Chicago Council of Foreign Relations
  - Childs, Marquis
  - China (Box 50)
    - General
    - Agriculture (Box 51)
    - Aircraft Corporation
    - Allied note to, 1919
    - American attitude toward
    - American aviators
    - American interests in
    - American trade with
    - Andrews, Roy Chapman, articles by
    - Anti-Christian movement
    - Anti-foreign feeling
    - Armed Forces
    - Arms Embargo
    - Arms sales to
    - Arnold, Julean, "Salient Facts About,"
    - Art
    - Articles by Hornbeck
    - Assistance to
      - 1933-1938
      - 1933-1942 (Box 52)
      - 1943 (Box 53)
      - Committee on Aid to China
      - Committee on Aid to China, Washington
      - Famine Relief U.S.A.
      - Loans
      - Promises of Aid to
      - Relief
      - United China Relief (Box 54)
    - Attaches
    - Austin, F. Britten, "The Hidden Forces in China"
    - Baltimore Conference
    - Bandits and pirates
    - Banks
    - Barnett, Doak
    - Bashford, Bishop
    - Beggars
    - Bennett, James W.
    - Bethlehem Steel Company Contract
    - Bibliography
    - Bibliography, Cordier on
    - Bingham, color line
    - Bolshevism in (Box 55)
    - Bonsal, Stephen, "China and the 'Foreign Devils'"
    - Book reviews
    - Bombings, Chungking
    - Bombings, Chungking (Tutuila)
    - Boxer Indemnity
    - Boxer Uprising
    - Boy Emperor
    - Boycott, 1905
    - Boycott
    - Bristol in
    - British Chamber of Commerce, Resolution, 1919
    - British Government note to League, 1927 January 27
    - British in
    - British Note, 1926
    - British Policy
    - "Browbeating" (Rhea), 1915
    - Bureau of Markets
    - Burma Road
    - Cabinets, 1921 December 25 (Box 56)
    - Calendar, 1926
    - California College in
    - Campbell, C. W.
    - Canton City Charter
    - Canton Government, 1921
    - Cartoons and pictures
    - Cassell Contract
    - Ceramic Art, "Sung Chien Sky Blue" Heavenly Ball Vase
    - Chambers of Commerce
    - Chang Hsueh Liang, Ruler of Manchuria, 1929
    - Chang Tso-Lin
    - Characteristics
    - Chen, Eugene
    - Cheng Chiatun Affair, 1916
      See also Japanese Demands on China.
    - Child, R. W., on war in
    - China-America Council of Industry
    - China, a Social-Political-Economic Survey
    - China Electric Company
    - China Foundation (Box 57)
    - China Fund, The
    - China House
    - China Information Service
    - China Institute in America, 1961-1965
    - China Institute Bulletin
    - China National Aviation Corporation (Box 58)
    - "China News and Views"
    - "China Today: Political," letters on
    - China Today (Earl Swisher, World Peace Federation), 1931
    - China's Capacity
    - China's Civil Service, Dr. Hsieh's Thesis
    - Chinchow, bombing of, etc.
    - Chinchow Neutral Zone
    - Chinese (Box 59)
      - General
      - Ambassador Chengting Thomas Wang
      - Ambassador Sao-Ke Alfred Sze
      - Ambassador Wei Tao-Ming
      - Broadcasts
      - Characteristics
      - Claims, Hornbeck to E. T. W., 1919 May 2
      - Customs Revenues
      - Eastern Railway
      - Embassy (Box 60)
      - Emigration
      - Exclusion
      - In Dutch East Indies
      - Institute of Technical Training
      - Japanese Situation, Saturday Lunch Club Speech, Madison, Wisconsin, 1915
      - Lee, Frank, Ex-Vice Minister for Foreign Affairs of China
      - Minister Sao-Ke Alfred Sze
      - W. W. Yen
      - Name and cards
      - News Service
      - Press
      - Press Agency
      - Social and Political Science Review
      - Student's Annual Conference, 1916
      - Studies: Library of Congress, Division of Chinese Literature, East Asiatic Books
      - Studies in American colleges and universities, 1956
      - Yui, Dr. David
    - Chiu, Alfred Kaiming, "Classification in China"; Libraries of Chinese Books in America
    - Christianity in
    - Chronology, 1911-1952 (Box 61)
    - Citizenship
    - Civil Service
    - Clark, Grover, articles by
    - Clippings and pamphlets, early China (probably from Reinsch collection)
    - Clippings (Box 62)
      - Early China (probably from Reinsch collection)
      - 1909-1910, 1912
      - Appointment and resignation of diplomatic officials, 1916-1918 (Box 63)
      - Chinese diplomacy, local regulations and foreign agreements, 1916-1918
      - Civil strife in China, friction between north and south, bandits, 1916-1918
      - China's resent and future trade, 1916-1918
      - European war to Far East, 1918
      - Finances, 1918
      - Inter-Allied problems, international law, 1918
      - Chiefly mounted, 1918-1919 (Box 64)
      - Chiefly mounted, 1922 (Box 65)
      - 1922
      - 1922-1924
      - 1922-1924 (Box 66)
      - Chiefly mounted, 1923
      - 1916-1933 (Box 67)
      - 1941-1948 (Box 68)
      - 1948-1949 (Box 69)
      - 1950-1951 (Box 70)
    - Colleges
    - Commerce and industry
    - Commission on Claims
    - Communications
    - Communism in
    - Communist
    - Communist in 1949
    - Communist and Asia
    - Concessions
    - Conditions in
    - Confucianism
    - Conservancy work (from Reinsch collection) (Box 71)
    - Consortium
    - Consortium, Hornbeck memo to Stevens, 1921
    - Consortium and six powers
    - Consortium, the new
    - Consortium and U.S.
    - Consortium (Thomas; Williams)
    - Constitution of 1923, Dr. Young's translation (Box 72)
    - Constitutions
    - Consular precedents
    - Contracts, State Department publications
    - Coolidge, President, Statement of Policy, April 25, 1927
    - Cotton and cotton mills
    - Courses at Columbia University, 1924, 1925
    - Crane, Charles R., in China
    - Culture
    - Currency reform
    - Curtis, Lionel, on China
    - Debts, inadequately secured obligations
    - Defense Supplies, Inc.
    - Deforestation
    - Dennet, Tyler, articles
    - Department of Commerce Committee
    - Dewey, J., China, Japan and the U.S.A.
    - Diplomatic Corps
    - Diplomatic history
    - Drama
    - Dynasties
    - Dynasties, Manchu
    - Earthquake
    - Economic (Box 73)
    - Economic activity of Japan in China
    - Economic Resources
    - Edmunds, "Thirty Thousand Miles in China" (Box 74)
    - Education
    - Elections, 1916, bibliography
    - Embassy to Netherlands
    - Empress Dowager
    - Engineering in
    - Essay contest
    - Examination system
    - Extraterritoriality
      - General
      - General (Box 75)
      - Bibliography
      - Clippings
      - Commissions, 1926
      - Commissions
      - Judicial
      - Pledges of G.B., U.S. and Japan; treaty clauses
      - Japan; treaty clauses
      - Schurman on, 1925
      - Diplomatic correspondence, 1922-1924 (Box 76)
      - China and U.S.
    - Family (Box 77)
    - Famine
    - Famine relief
    - Far Eastern Review
    - Federal wireless contract
    - Feethem report
    - Ferguson, "After Forty Years"
    - Finance
    - Finance, 1923, 1924, 1928
    - Finance, Pacific Development Corporation
    - Finance (Box 78)
    - Financial
    - Flood relief, note
    - Food
    - Foreign advisors, Sir Robert Hart
    - Foreign armed forces in
    - Foreign debts, 1920
    - Foreign interests, open door and spheres of influence policies, outline
    - Foreign interests in
    - Foreign military forces in, 1930
    - Foreign Office
    - Foreign policy
    - Foreign relations
    - Foreign relations, U.S., index to
    - Foreign relations, 1914-1917 (Tyau)
    - Foreign troops in, 1926
    - Geography
    - Geology (Box 79)
    - Germans in
    - Germany (see also Shantung)
    - Germany, after the war
    - Germany, Commercial Treaty, 1921
    - Germany, relations before and after the war, V. Rosthorn
    - Gilbert, Rodney, articles on
    - Glossary
    - Good will
    - Goodnow, Frank J., "Reform in China," 1915
    - Gordon, Charles
    - Gosford, on
    - Government
    - Government and President
    - Government Republican
    - Grand Canal Loan, note
    - Great Britain
    - Great Wall
    - Great Wall, A. Warwick
    - Guenther, Louis, "Stumbling China, 1930"
    - Guilds, Chinese, by Minister Denby
    - Haichow, Port of
    - Hamilton, M. M., "China in 1931"
    - Hangchow
    - Hankow
    - Hankow Concession, February 1927
    - Hankow situation
    - Harbin, municipal administration
    - Hart, Sir Robert
    - Hawkins' outline
    - Hay, John
    - Hedin, Sven
    - Hengyang
    - History
    - History dates
    - Ho Ping Song (Box 80)
    - Ho Ping Song, S. K. Hornbeck manuscript
    - Hobart, Alice, articles
    - Honjo, Lieutenant General, Proclamation of
    - Hsia, Dr. C. L.
    - Hsiung Shih-Fie, General (Hsiung Shih-Hui, General)
    - Huh Shih, Doctor
    - Hukuang, loan
    - Hukuang railway loan contract
    - Immigration (Box 81)
    - Immigration into Mexico
    - Industrial Cooperatives (Box 82)
    - Industrial and commercial progress
    - Industrial program
    - Industrialization (see China, Economic)
    - Inland Waters (navigation)
    - Institute in America
    - Intellectual rebirth
    - International Institute of China
    - International relations
    - "Intervention," Chicago Tribune
    - Investments
    - Iron
    - Iron Mines
    - Jade
    - Japan-China agreements, 1915
    - Japan, boycott
    - Japan, boycotts, Chinese
    - Japan Chientao Treaty
    - Japan, Chinese-Japanese Agreement, signed Shanghai May 5, 1932
    - Japan, Chinese-Japanese Rapprochement
    - Japan and China, Crozier on
    - Japan, cruisers
    - "Japan in China," by Charles D. Tenney
    - Japan negotiations, 1915
    - Japan, military pact
    - Japan and China, miscellaneous (Box 83)
    - Japan, policy in, Roy Anderson on, 1922
    - Japan policy toward
    - Japanese emigration to
    - Japanese-Chinese hostilities, September, 1937
    - Japanese-Chinese hostilities, October, 1937
    - Japan, Ho-Umezu Agreement
    - Japanese immigration to
    - Japan, roots of misunderstanding
    - Japanese smuggling in
    - Japan-China situation, reflections
    - Japanese-China War
    - Jordan, Sir John on, 1925
    - Kang, Yu-Wei (Box 84)
    - Kearny, Commodore Lawrence
    - Kellogg Policy Statement, January 27, 1927
    - Knox neutralization proposals
    - Knox policy, 1909-1910
    - Koo, T. Z., "What China Fights for," 1927
    - Kuomintang News Service
    - Kwang Chow Wan
    - Kwantung, the Cassell contract and the Canton-Hankow Railway
    - "Labor Movement in 1928," by S. K. Sheldon Tso
    - Lamont, T. W., "America and the Far East," 1920
    - Land of contrasts
    - Land tenure in
    - "Land Utilization in China, 1927," by Baker
    - Language
    - Latourette, Kenneth Scott
      - "China, the United States and the War; Shantung and Its Status"
      - "Early Relations Between the United States and China," bibliography
      - Outline of China under the Republic
      - Syllabus
      - "Two Years After Paris"
    - Law codes
    - Law (Escarra)
    - League of Nations, London, May 15, 1919
    - Legations, diplomatic lists
    - Legation dispatches, 1919
    - Lend-Lease
    - Li Hung Chang, memoirs
    - Liang Chi-Chao, "China and World Peace"
    - Liang Chi-Chao
    - Likin (Box 85)
    - Likin, correspondence with G. G. Wilson, 1925
    - Likin System, memo by S. K. Hornbeck, 1924
    - Likin and surtaxes, Bureau of International Research Peking, China 1925
    - Limitation of Armaments
    - Literature, drama (Box 86)
    - Literature, poetry
    - Loans
    - Lobby
    - Lyon, G. A., "Safety in China," 1929
    - Macao, 1922 (Box 87)
    - Macao question
    - Main, Doctor Duncan
    - Manchuria
    - Manning, W. R., "China and the Powers Since the Boxer Movement," 1910
    - Marcy, W. L. (See China: Papers: Reinsch acquisition)
    - Maritime Customs Service
    - Mass education
    - Mayers's unification plan
    - McKenzie, R. D., "When the East Meets West," 1928
    - McLane, Robert M., correspondence and papers, 1954 (See China: Papers: Reinsch acquisition) (Box 88)
    - Medicine in
    - Memorandum regarding, by W. H. G. and S. K. Hornbeck, December 1926
    - Mencius and other reformers (Macklin)
    - Merrill, Commissioner, on China
    - Metals and railroads, Rhea, F. L.
    - Military
    - Military Intelligence Department, estimate
    - Millard, Thomas F.
    - Miller, Rex, on, 1927
    - Mining regulations
    - Missions
    - "Moderne, La Chine," 1920
    - Mongolia
    - Moon Year (Box 89)
    - Morse's International Relations, I - II
    - Morse, "Repayment"
    - Mukden Incident
    - Nanking Incident, March 24, 1927
    - Nanking situation
    - National Anthem
    - National government, 1928
    - Nationalism
    - Nationalist Manifesto, 1927
    - National movements
    - "The Nationalist Movement and a Ray of Hope," Christian Science Monitor, 1927
    - Nationalist propaganda
    - Nationalists
    - Needs: "What China Needs Today," by Marshal Feng Yu-Hsiang, 1925
    - Nestorian Tablet at Sianfu
    - Newchwang, Port of, 1920
    - North China Union Language School
    - North vs. South
    - Note to China and Japan, January 7, 1932
    - Notes
    - O'Brien letters (Box 90)
    - Oil
    - Open Door Policy
      - American policy
      - Antung Customs Agreement
      - Anti-Open Door agreements
      - Berlin Act
      - Equal opportunity (Box 91)
      - Equal treatment of territorial interests of China
      - European powers in China
      - Excerpts from official documents (complete)
      - Far East, U.S. and
      - France in Yunnan up to 1914
      - Gardiner, W. H., on
      - Hughes, 1921
      - Japan
      - Jenk's articles, 1916-1917
      - Knox neutralization policy
      - Lansing-Ishii Agreement and "Special Interests"
      - Materials for Special....
      - Memoranda and reports
      - Memoranda and reports (Box 92)
      - Miscellaneous
      - Notes, U.S. 1915, U.S. Japanese-Chinese demands
      - Pledges, treaty
      - Port Arthur and Talienwan Lease. Also extension of Manchuria Railway
      - Portsmouth Treaty
      - Practice in regions other than Manchuria up to 1914
      - Railways, Tientsin-Pukow
      - Rockhill, Open Door memo
      - Russia in Manchuria, 1898-1905
      - Saturday Review
      - South Manchuria
      - South Manchuria Railway
      - Spheres of influence
      - Spheres of influence, Japanese
      - Spheres of interest, France
      - U.S. efforts, Beyer
      - Wallace on
      - Yalu Timber Concession
      - Yunnan, France in
    - Opium (Box 93)
      - General
      - 1917 (Box 94)
      - Conference, Geneva, 1924
      - Habit-forming drugs
      - Question in 1916
      - Smith, R. to 1918
    - "Oriental Culture"
    - "Origins of the Chinese," by E. T. Williams
    - O'Shea case
    - Papers, Reinsch acquisition
    - Pacific Review, Far East articles, 1921
    - Paris Conference
    - Parker, Peter, correspondence etc. (See: China: Papers: Reinsch acquisition)
    - Parker's (Peter) Problem
    - "A Party Platform Proposal," by S. K. H.
    - Peace
    - Peffer, Nathaniel, articles
    - Peiping - Tientsin area
    - Peking, Legation Quarter
    - Personages
    - Personalities, photographs (Box 95)
    - Personages
    - Philosophers
    - Philosophy of life
    - Pidgin English
    - Policy, 1948, memo to Butterworth, by S. K. Hornbeck
    - Policy
    - Political, 1930
    - Political, 1932
    - Political parties (Loh Ho)
    - Political puzzle, politics to August 1917
    - Political puzzle
    - Political thought, modern bibliography
    - Politics
    - Politics, 1912-1922
    - Politics, June 1916-March 1917
    - Politics to August 1917
    - Politics, 1922-1923
    - Politics, 1927
    - Policy of Chinese Government
    - Policy of powers toward
    - Porter Resolution, January 4, 1927 (Box 96)
    - Porter, Stephen G., on 1929
    - Post offices in, question of abolishing foreign
    - Postal Administration
    - Postwar
    - Price, Maurice
    - Problems
    - Products
    - Progress, Baker
    - Prophesies, 1907
    - Protest of May 1915
    - Protocol 1901
    - Protocols of 1905
    - Provinces, Political Alignment, 1921
    - Provincial autonomy movement
    - Puppet regimes in
    - Puto
    - Quarterly
    - Quigley, Harold S. articles by
    - Railways, 5.0 folders)
    - Railway, Chinese Eastern (Box 97)
    - Railway, Chinese Eastern, correspondence with Chang Tao-Shing, 1934
    - Railway, concessions
    - Railways, expert suggestions
    - Railways, Japanese in
    - Railway, Kirin, and extension (See Korea: Railways, new)
    - Railways and loans in China (Rea, G. B., E. D. 1919)
    - "Railway Loans to the Chinese Government as a Means of Securing a Market for Railways Materials and Equipment," A. P. Winston
    - Railway Loans, 1909 (C. C. Wang, 1910)
    - Railways, Peking - Suiyuan
    - Railway Plans (Reinsch, Baker, Witham)
    - Recognition
    - Reconstruction
    - Reconstruction and rebellion, 1913
    - Red China, 2.0 folders)
    - Red China (Box 98)
    - Red China, articles by Dr. Sripati Chandrasekhar
    - Red China, Mid Report on, 1945
    - Red China (L. Taire, R. Guillian, R. Gilbert, Horoth, and miscellaneous)
    - Red Cross (Box 99)
    - Reforms
    - Reform Decrees, 1898
    - Reforms, legal
    - Reforms, movement
    - Reforms, social
    - Reinsch, Paul S.
    - Relations, China-Great Britain
    - Religions
    - Religions, Taoism
    - Roads
    - Republic
    - Republic, 1914, comment on by Rockhill, Morrison and Bland
    - Republic, Government, Foundations for Republic (See China: Social Institution as Background)
    - Republic Lecture, October 25, 1916
    - Republic, return to monarchy, 1915
    - Republic, return to Republic, 1916
    - Republic, Sino-American Mutual Defense Treaty, December 1954
    - Research (Box 100)
    - Resources
    - Revenues and taxation
    - Revolution
    - Revolution, "A Year of New Cathay," 1911-1912
    - Ridge, "Chinese Backgrounds"
    - Roads
    - Rockefeller Foundation, Peking, 1924
    - Rockhill, W. W., memo, 1899
    - Rockhill, W. W., papers of
    - Roots, John McC., "China Now"
    - Rugs
    - Russia, 2.0 folders)
    - Russia (Box 101)
    - Russian relations, Ignatieff Mission, 1860
    - Russo-Chinese dispute, 1929 (See also Soviet Russia)
    - Russo-Chinese relations
    - Salt Gabelle
    - Schurman on, 1929
    - Screen from Imperial Palace
    - Secret Protocols of 1905
    - Secret Societies
    - Seward, William to Anson Burlingame about Sir Frederick Bruce and the "Scotland" (Reinsch), March 24, 1864
    - Sforza, Count Carlo "China-Republic or Empire?" 1928
    - Shanghai Import and Export Co., about Simmons Co.
    - Shanghai Incident of 1925
    - Shanghai International Settlement
    - Shanghai, Kellogg re
    - Shanghai, Land Regulation, 1848 (See: China: Papers: Reinsch acquisition)
    - Shanghai Mixed Court
    - Shanghai, by Palmer, F.
    - Shanghai, "A World Port," 1924
    - Shantung (Box 102)
      - General
      - Since 1914
      - October 5, 1921
      - 1924
      - Chen's telegram on Sino-Japanese controversy
      - China's efforts, 1914 and after
      - China's claim
      - Chinese reply to Japanese proposals, October 1921
      - Comments by Weale
      - Crane, Charles R., letter on
      - Famous cities of (See also "MacMurray" in general file)
      - Gilchrist, Huntington, "Germany in China," Harvard University, 1916
      - In the Press, during the Peace Conference
      - Japan in
      - Japan in, index
      - Japanese activities in
      - Lecture, Hornbeck, 1920
      - Legal phases of the Shantung question, Quigley
      - Liang Chi Chao on
      - Miscellaneous
      - Norton, H. K., Japan's Aim in Shangtung
      - Northcliffe on
      - Peace Conference, Paris
      - Ratification of Treaty of 1922 by Japan
      - "Shantung", chapter for Book VI, History of the Peace Conference; includes correspondence with Harold Temperley
      - "Shantung Question," Latourette
      - Sino-Japanese Relations, 1921
      - "Spheres of Interest"
      - Telegram, Eugene Chen
    - Shepherd, William C., "China as a Customer" (Box 103)
    - Ship-building
    - Silk
    - Sino-American Tariff Treaty of 1928, Chinese interpretation of
    - Situation in 1927, outline for lecture or article
    - Slavery in Hong Kong
    - Social
    - Social and Political Science Association
    - Social Basis, by F. W. Williams
    - "Social Institutions as a Background for Republican Government," by E. T. Williams, discussion by S. K. Hornbeck
    - Socialism
    - Society
    - Society of America
    - Sokolsky, George E., 1927
    - Soong, T. V. (Chinese Minister of Finance)
    - Soviet Russia, 1929, Chinese Eastern Railway